Today on the podcast, I sat down with Brian Foster, the global head of wholesale at Coinbase.
In this conversation, we discuss the shifting environment for banks, broker dealers and
governments in the digital asset market and how Coinbase has evolved their business to work with
many of these new entrants to the ecosystem. I think you'll enjoy this one. So without further
ado, here's my conversation with Brian Foster. Matt Walsh and Nick Carter are partners at Castle
Island Ventures. All of these expressed by them or the guests on this podcast are solely their
opinions and do not reflect the opinions of Castle Island Ventures. Guests and hosts may
maintain positions in the assets discussed in this podcast. You should not treat any opinion
expressed by anyone on this podcast as a specific inducement to make a particular investment or
follow a particular strategy, but only as an expression of their personal opinion. This
podcast is for informational purposes only. Brought down by bad mortgage investments,
Lehman, which has 25,000 employees, will be liquidated. The federal government loans
American International Group, AIG, $85 billion. This is a different kind of market and the Fed
is asleep. The federal government is stepping in to stabilize Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac,
the two mortgage giants that have been threatened by the housing crisis. The Bank of England has
pumped 75 billion pounds more into Britain's ailing economy with a new round of quantitative
easing. They print a couple trillion dollars and all of a sudden people start to worry. So out of
this worry, we have something called the Bitcoin. Bitcoin. Well, Brian, welcome back to the podcast.
It's exciting to have you. Thanks a lot, Matt, for having me on. So we're going to talk a lot about
the institutional client segment today, but maybe for those who haven't heard your prior
appearance on the podcast, do you want to just tee us up with who you are and what you do at Coinbase?
Sure. So I joined Coinbase back in 2019 to help get our institutional practice off the ground
alongside a few amazing colleagues. And we've really been in an all out sprint since then,
and have built what's now a big business where we have what we think is the leading institutional
product suite and a dream roster of clients who we feel super fortunate to get to work with.
And within that today, I look after a few of these client businesses. The first is our wholesale
business, where we tower about 200 leading banks, brokers, fintechs, exchanges, payment firms
who use our institutional infrastructure to build and run their own crypto products.
The second is our ETF business, where we help trade and safeguard just under about 100 billion
of crypto on behalf of ETF issuers and their clients. And the third is our government practice,
where we work with U.S. federal and state agencies and also other governments around the world to
really help them navigate an increasingly wide range of crypto activity. And before all this at
Coinbase, I worked in a product and strategy role at a crypto startup called Curve, which was
acquired by PayPal. And before that, worked in venture investing in crypto, cybersecurity,
and really started out my career doing a few different startups, including one of my own and
another in the FX trading space, which is how I originally bumped into the crypto world.
Yeah, that was a great story. I think you told that on the first time around. I think you were
getting paid in Bitcoin by Ty Danko back in the day. That's right. We did finagle that.
It's a good way to get introduced to the sector. And a ton has changed. Since the last time you
were on this podcast, you think about the businesses that you work in over at Coinbase.
There were no ETFs last time you were on the podcast. Banks were completely shut out from
this industry. SAP 121 was in effect. How has the world changed for you, just given everything
that's happened over the past few months? Well, it's changed a ton. You're definitely
right. So I think maybe in terms of the banks, brokers, and exchanges, this category that we
call wholesale, they're definitely on the move in a big way. And we think this is exciting for the
industry. For us, what it really means is it's go time for the wholesale business. And this is a
business we don't really make a ton of noise about publicly, but we think it's going to be an area
of accelerating growth for us. I think people sometimes understandably look at these firms
and what they're doing and think maybe they compete with Coinbase. And that's partially
true. But in fact, behind the curtain, a lot of them are routing their client trading to us,
using us for subcustody, prop trading, getting active on base, USDC, stablecoin payments,
and more. And so when we look at these firms, we think that there are a ton of jobs to be done
here. And we're fortunate to really have the product threats and the team to rise to the
occasion. So I think what this all really means is that we view these firms as our partners.
And we're excited to hold out our infrastructure to power them, really similarly to how we did it with
the ETFs. And generally, we find that when large, incredible firms come into the market,
they grow the pie. It's great for users and investors to see that. And of course, it's great
for Coinbase as well. I think it's worth noting that this has been a little bit of a change for
Coinbase as a firm and one we've been pretty deliberate about. We're a much broader company
than we used to be. We still have a large branded first party business for retail institutional
clients that people know well, but we're now far down the path of transforming ourselves into also
being an infrastructure company. And our CEO Brian talked about this the other week on our earnings
call with Coinbase Prime, CDP and Base. These are just a couple of our big infrastructure bets that
are just really starting to take off. So maybe I'll just briefly get a little more concrete on
what we're doing with the banks, brokers specifically. As you know well, Matt, most of
the large ones are doing something at this point, which is exciting. And we're working with the
majority of them. I think that the record breaking growth of the ETFs in crypto really made this
sort of impossible for them to ignore. It's kind of in their backyard now. The clients are trading
and it's a big thing. So we've seen a little bit of variation by geography. The ex-US market went
first. Brazil, parts of Asia, parts of Europe have been fast moving where regulation has been
clearest. Now we're getting this moment where the US is getting to play catch up. And so the current
state of play as we talk to these firms is that they're in the process of really reasoning through
how to partner, how to build, what products to prioritize first. So we're seeing some are
trying to build some of the stack and partner on the rest. Others are partnering with us on most of
it, but we don't see a ton of firms trying to do everything themselves. And I'd say this is a thing
we kind of anticipated because we know from firsthand experience how hard it is to do crypto
well. So one thing we've been really deliberate about as we built out the wholesale and the other
infrastructure businesses is that we've really designed our products to be consumed modularly.
So we want to be able to approach these partners and plug into them no matter what their strategy
is. So hopefully this gives people a little bit of a better sense of what's going on behind the
scenes. And by the way, I'll just add, this is a Coinbase partnership story around product on our
side, but it's worth mentioning that in parallel to all this, we work really closely with a lot of
the large financial institutions in the other direction as well, where they power the on-ramps
for our first party businesses. They provide services to our corporate treasury, et cetera.
So these are often large and multidimensional relationships.
That's an awesome overview. And obviously all banks are different to some degree and
their revenue levers vary depending on which bank you're looking at. The private wealth channel
obviously was an early adopter to ETFs. I guess you'd say early, but maybe not as early as
compared to retail and some of the independent RIAs. But curious how you guys think about it in
terms of the banks that might be interested in a spot relationship with Coinbase versus a bank
that might be more interested in just an ETF relationship versus maybe even something totally
different around stable coins. How do you guys segment the go-to-market for the wholesale
business depending on the underlying bank? The reality is a bank is really an amalgamation
of a lot of different businesses and we can think of each one of those businesses like a client. So
in some cases we find that the soft spot is doing something quickly in the wealth practice
that might mean kind of cohabitating client accounts with advisors or supporting the educational
effort around ETFs and related due diligence. In other cases, they really want to lean into
payments and stable coins or something else. And so I think we try to kind of resource these in
the right way, put the right coverage teams in place and think of them like kind of 10 businesses
and 1 if that makes sense. Yeah, that makes a ton of sense. So when you look at some of these
banks and these brokers, I guess the question is what's going to make them succeed or fail?
And I suspect that getting an early start is probably part of that. But curious how you guys
look at that in terms of who the right partners ought to be and who's best positioned here.
We definitely have some opinions about this, having led more of these types of
partnerships and integrations than probably anyone across multiple market cycles, I'll add,
as things have changed a lot and there's been volatility and people have come and gone for
some of these places. I think there's great lessons in the ETF issuers as well. They just
went through a similar journey and for the most part hit a lot of home runs. So I think the way
that I think about this, if I zoom way out, if I'm on the board of one of these banks or brokers
evaluating the crypto strategy, there's a few really important questions I'm asking.
And I think the most important one of all where I'd start is how do I minimize risk to my firm
and to my clients? No matter how excited I am about digital assets, and it's great by the way
that a lot of firms are there at this point, I'm still not putting my net interest margin machine
at risk for this. And I'm not going to cut corners and risk getting stuck with big fine from one of
my regulators. So I think that starts with security and asset protection above all else. You have to
nail that and really approach it with a lot of rigor. Next, the thing I'm thinking about from a
product perspective is can I build things that are actually going to work for my clients in
today's market? I can't be building for five years ago. This market moves too fast. So for instance,
standalone custody is kind of dead in the water from our point of view. Clients are demanding
far more than that. They need support for the entire transaction lifecycle,
financing, multi-asset support, staking, spot and derivatives, stable coins and payments.
And that threshold of requirements for clients just keeps rising.
So next is in terms of execution. Can I do something here quickly? I don't want to take
four or five years to get to market. This is a high growth race. So I have to figure out how to
break some glass and make my organization move faster than it might normally. Of course, there's
another commercial question, which is how will the business model work? How am I rationalizing my
costs to rent or install this infrastructure to do this? And how do I de-risk those economics to
make sure this is a winner? And maybe the last thing I'll add is that whatever platform I set up,
I really want to make sure that it gives me a high ceiling for growth and upside
in the future. And you have to consider, are the decisions that I'm going to make today
end up limiting my options in a year or two where I have to rip things out and start over?
And I say this just because we've seen a little bit of this one, including recently,
where certain crypto partners maybe have failed or not had the resources to keep their foot on the
gas throughout the cycle or otherwise been off sides from a regulatory perspective. And so we
want to make sure that these partners of ours who are banks and brokers aren't getting stuck.
And to kind of bring this all home, I'd say what we found is that when firms ask these questions
and then do the calculus correctly, a lot of roads lead to partnership with Coinbase.
So just going quickly, today, you can rent out our market leading product suite for a handful
of basis points and be profitable from day one. The market's really matured commercially and
there's ways to do this where you don't have to shell out tens of billions in capex or try to go
buy a bunch of expensive and specialized crypto talent. You can go fast. We're ready. Do it at
your own speed. You're sort of in control of your own destiny there if you want to move quickly.
In terms of upside, what we're really focused on is continuing to really build at the frontier
from a product perspective to make sure that our partners and clients are unconstrained
with how they develop product as the market unfolds. And of course, most importantly,
on this question of risk, we really think of ourselves as being a sort of risk transfer
mechanism here, right? We want to enable partners to be able to transfer their risk to a firm who
knows how to handle it. And for example, you can draft off of what's almost certainly the
largest security budget in crypto at Coinbase instead of having to learn how to do this from
scratch. So this is how we think about checking these really big boxes that are being presented
by decision makers. I'll say that we really commend all the firms who have made moves and
tried something, whether that's build or a partnership. It's super challenging, as you
know, Matt, to try to get a large organization to move and address a fast moving new market like
this. So my view is like there's a special place in heaven for people inside of large organizations
who are leading the charge on crypto. But if I had to take out my crystal ball, I think what we see
over the next few years is that these firms who intelligently partner are going to be in the best
position to win. They're going to, I think, be able to leapfrog maybe some of the ones who have
overbuilt or picked the wrong partner and might be getting stuck. So that's all shaking out in
real time right now. From our perspective, we're super excited for this and are hard at work arming
the firms who want to partner, whether that's partially or fully. We want to really help bring
the whole weight of our firm and help those partners build a really durable business for
their clients. It's really interesting because if you look at the past couple of years, there's
been these kind of de-risking milestones that allow more entrance to this market. So you have
the ETFs getting approved is a big one. Saab 121 going away is a big one. I would have to think
a stable coin bill and eventually a market structure bill would be really big for your
business. So how do you think about those unlocks? And I guess how did the customers,
how did the partners think about just regulatory clarity on those two issues in terms of entering
this market? Yeah, it's a great point. I think that the pace that Congress moves is something
that is sometimes a little bit unpredictable and it can take a while. But you're certainly
right that these two efforts, if they were to come to fruition, would make a huge impact
on the market. I think that stable coins have suddenly really grown up and become a thing that
people are starting to accept is not going away. We'll see, I think, tons more growth from the
corporate segment and a lot of these clients who the banks and brokers are working with
are going to start demanding those types of solutions. So legislation that ultimately
opens this market up and allows people to participate in it is going to be a boon for
that category of stable coins and payments. And on the market structure side, I think just having
the confidence to know how these assets are going to be classified, and then also specifically
opening up this world of tokenization, it just grows the market massively. We're talking about
much more than just native crypto assets now in this scenario where that type of rulemaking plays
out. And we think that's super exciting. It's great for us and it's great for these other
institutions as well. It's been interesting to look at the inside of some of these banks
over the past few years and kind of who gets it and who doesn't get it. Some of these banks have
had crypto teams very quietly operating for years and years and actually building things,
in some cases partnering. Others, I get the sense that they don't have anyone. They're sort of
starting from scratch. So you'd think that M&A would be part of the solution here at some point.
How do you think about what that would look like for banks to get into this sector via M&A?
It's a great question. I said it right back and ask you the same one. I think from my perspective,
M&A looks great on paper and there are probably a lot of financial institutions who are thinking
about this as one option and maybe want to scoop up crypto specialists at the right moment. I think
it could work in a few cases, but you have some challenges here to navigate. One is that a lot of
the players in the crypto service provider world are pretty narrowly focused specialists. And so
you can't solve maybe all of the problems you have by acquiring. Maybe some tuck-ins here can work,
but I don't think there's a single silver bullet. The other problem I see
broadly is that you sort of have a super wide bid-ask spread on valuation between some of these
companies and there would be acquirers. So in the private markets, you have founders and VCs
marking these companies series A's and B's with the expectation that Bitcoin's going to a million.
And that might be right. I personally agree with it, but it's, I think, sometimes a tough sell to
a bank or a broker, which is trading at maybe three to five times your revenue and maybe doesn't
want to bet the farm on that kind of optimistic outcome. So you and I have talked a lot, Matt,
over the years about tokenization. Maybe that's the thing, sort of the market growing event that
changes the math for some of these players to justify these types of acquisitions. And if we
see this really explode in the next year or two with policy change, maybe they'll want to start
paying up. This goes from being really an upside question of having a crypto native business that
can generate a lot of new growth to being more of an existential one, right? Where we're talking
about taking a firm's entire asset base and needing to sort of re-engineer it to live on chain.
And that's like an existential meteor. So maybe as that meteor gets a bit closer, it changes the
math. What do you think? I'm curious for your perspective, given your vantage point as a
venture investor. Well, I guess custody is really the tricky one to think about because on one hand,
you could see the logic of M&A if you're a bank just to get to the market, right? You want to go
fast and you want to just have a team out of the gate and maybe you want to lock that team up for
a while. This question with some of these centralized custodians is, are they serving
customers that you even want to serve as the bank? And is the asset mix the right asset mix? And so
you wouldn't want to buy something and then shut down 80% of the assets because you only want to
focus on, I don't know, the top 10 cryptocurrencies, for instance. So I think it's a little challenging.
The other issue, of course, is just you brought up the valuation point, but are these actually
creative acquisitions to the banks or not? And how do you think about that? So that's probably
the trickiest area from where I sit. And not to mention the fact that there aren't that many to
buy. So some of these banks might just be forced to partner or try to build their own, which I think
building your own would take quite a while. Yeah, I think that's right. Makes good sense.
So dovetailing a little bit, maybe let's talk about the ETFs. I mean, these have been
wildly successful. I thought they would be. I don't know if I thought they would be as successful
as they have been. Did you anticipate this? Was this sort of a foreseeable thing from where you sit?
Well, I'd be lying if I said yes to this decree. I think it's exceeded probably all of our
expectations just in terms of how fast the asset gathering happened here. And it's been such a boon
for the industry. I'll also say from our point of view, thank God it worked out. We sort of
bet big on it in terms of our product prioritization last year. It's funny, we're often proud of the
things we've built in crypto land and we should be. Companies like Coin Days have built their own
distribution from scratch, brick by brick, and that's working well. But it's really awe-inspiring
to see the distribution firepower that many of these partners of ours in TradFi have. And it
makes me glad that we're on the same team. And I think also really reinforces for us the importance
of this infrastructure strategy we have. So I think this is just the start, despite the kind
of staggering numbers and having basically in excess of 100 billion here, we really only have
simple products so far, right? Bitcoin and ETH have been great. I think single asset beta exposure
is just the beginning. So I won't speak to things that aren't public, but you can see what's in some
of these recent filings and make some inferences. Staking support for more assets beyond Bitcoin
and ETH, multi-asset ETFs and more distribution and inclusion in model portfolios as well
are all huge focus areas for us right now. So maybe I'll hit on staking for a minute just
because this is one that's top of mind and super technically interesting. We're spending a lot of
time on it. And Coinbase is live with staking and ETFs with partners of ours in Canada and Europe.
So we have a great playbook here that's proven and works well. But the challenge with this,
for those who don't know, is that when you're staking in an ETF, you sort of have to reconcile
the world of on-chain cryptophysics with that of C++ settlement and ETF ops. And shockingly,
neither one of these camps consider the other at the outset. And so we're now in the business of
super gluing them together after the fact. So specifically, the problem here is that you have
to account for crypto volatility shocks and make sure that there's enough liquidity when we have
downside events and everyone kind of runs for the fences at the same time, right? The unbonding
keys can get jammed in those scenarios, but the ETF still has an obligation for delivery.
So right now, in terms of things we're focused on in ETF land, we're doing a lot of scenario
modeling around that and trying to help arm our partners who are issuers to really be able to
work with us in an all-weather platform that's going to work rain or shine. And also think
more about what the future is going to look like as we navigate the Pectra upgrade on ETH and
also look at Solana and other chains as well. So I'm excited to see how this plays out. It's going
to be the issuers prerogative to decide how they want to do this and how much risk they want to
take. But we want to show up as a thoughtful partner supporting behind the scenes as we engage
them, their clients and regulators. And then just coming back to this idea of the model portfolio
theme for a minute, I think that what BlackRock announced recently this past week is a huge deal
and maybe bigger than people realize. So for those who might've missed it, you had inclusion
here of iBit in some of the alternative asset model portfolios at BlackRock.
And I wouldn't be surprised if we see more of that this year across the industry. As you know,
Matt, this is a business that has trillions in assets and really I think it provides a constant
passive bid. And so I think in the long term, this trend is going to have the effect of
absorbing more long-term capital and maybe dampening some volatility. So this is great
for asset prices and overall market health in the long term. The model portfolios thing is
fascinating. It also makes me wonder if some of these efforts to explore tokenization through
the lens of bringing alternative investments into model portfolios could be something that
actually gets a lot of interest if this effort is successful. Yeah, it's a great point. I think
people are going to get really creative. The aperture has obviously opened up from a regulatory
perspective on what people think is going to be permissible. So I expect to continue to see
a tidal wave of new filings throughout the year and for people to keep really pushing
the envelope on product. The staking one is another one I want to double click into.
And we've been talking about this a little bit on the podcast in terms of just how do you
operationalize this around some of the things you talked about, modeling worst-case events on
withdrawals and what if you're tied up on chain. As you point out, there is just a physics element
to this. And so the question is kind of who injects credit into that system and who bears
the risk. Do you think we have answers to how that's going to work in the U.S.? Or do we just
look at other jurisdictions and expect it to evolve in the same way? How do you think about that?
I think we do. Ultimately, the SEC is going to decide here what's permissible. And I think we
have to wait and see. Just like we did in the first round of the ETF filings, there was sort of
some back and forth. And then ultimately, basically guardrails that were put in place.
Here's the state of play. Everybody stay within these boundaries. But from a sort of feasibility
perspective, the playbook is there, right? At scale in other markets, we have staking inside
of ETFs working. The sort of order of operations here has been, I think, native custodial staking
and partial staking rather than staking the whole ETF seems to be the right place to start. That's
proven and works well. I think over time we could see sort of more creativity and augmentation of
that model as the issuers want to generate the highest returns possible for their clients. And
we're hard at work trying to help them build some of those solutions. I recently saw that there was
a private credit ETF that was approved. And I mean, that just seems a lot more complicated than basic
ETH or Solana staking. I think we should be able to figure out a good model here. I think you're
right. I think we have this extreme sense of duty to be good stewards collectively, us and the ETF
issuers. We want to get this right and make sure that these ETFs run smoothly and don't have any
blowups. But I'll say personally, I prefer that we do this in a kind of safe and controlled way
and continue this great track record of these things working well day in and day out. I think
that's going to be the best outcome for the industry long-term and just to get that balance
right and not jump the gun on anything. Yeah. And so you guys have a very clear lead here.
If you just look at market share for ETF custody, how do you see that playing out over time? I guess
the obvious question is, okay, the banks can come in. Do they get competitive with you over
what time horizon and how does Coinbase react to that? Yeah, it's a great question. So as a firm,
broadly we safeguard something around 12% of the entire crypto market cap. But as you point out,
within the ETF market, that number is much, much higher. So we had a really unique situation when
the ETFs launched where we sort of ran the table. And that might seem unusual, but we think it's
high market share we have in this category appropriately reflects the huge investment we
made in our security and custody platform ops around the ETFs and the market really voted with
their dollars. So it's also worth pointing out, this is a client segment with a small handful of
players who are highly regulated and discerning about risk. And I think that's a reality that
benefited us as well. In terms of backup custodians and what the mix might look like here, we think it
makes total sense for issuers to have operationally ready backups. We encourage that. It's good
practice. We're not, however, fans of spraying assets around within a singular ETF product.
I think this tends to compound operational risk because you're now multiplying settlements.
And crypto history has taught us that that's usually a risky thing to move stuff around
more than you need to. And by the way, a client's wondering, are they in the big custodian or the
one that offered the issuer a fee rebate? And so one challenge you have in crypto, which I don't
think is widely understood by outsiders, is that the dispersion of counterparty strength and quality
across custodians is super wide, unlike in traditional finance, where you have a few leaders
who are really large and battle tested. And so by virtually any measure, pick the dimension,
assets under custody, market cap, track records, security budget, client quality.
You have Coinbase and then really, in our opinion, a huge drop off.
So I think we're aware that there are some custodians who are probably selling quote,
unquote, diversification and waiving discounts at issuers to maybe generate a bit of growth.
And I think it's possible you'll see a small number of issuers take the bait there. But
ultimately, that's okay with us. I think we want to double down on the issuers who really view this
fiduciary position as sacred in the same way that we do and value what we're bringing to the table
as a partner. And by the way, competitively, I think that as these issuers compete with each
other, the ones who sort of don't compromise and really say, I want to have the biggest security
budget and all of this rigor going into my custodial setup are going to have a really easy
time selling against ones who maybe take a diversion path. So the market's going to ultimately
sniff that out. So this is all to say, I think we feel really confident about our position and
strategy, and we're going to keep pouring our resources in any way we can into these partnerships
where we feel like we have really a shared sense of priorities.
That makes a lot of sense. It kind of begs the obvious question around some of the potential
new entrants in TradFi. So if you just look at the global custody landscape and who's actually in
this, not a lot of them yet, right? Like it's getting too hard to ignore, I would say, for
all sorts of reasons. Tokenization, kind of the least of them, just these digital bear assets. So
I guess the question is, do these TradFi players have a better shot if they were to come into the
market? Yeah, let's see. It's a really exciting development. I think just from the signals I'm
getting from the market, the jury feels like it's still out. So first, we're partnering with some of
them on some custody. So there may be ways for this to make sense. But I think some of the more
homegrown solutions inside of some of the banks who are pursuing that path are going to need to
prove that they can win. And they're brand new to this and not quite there yet. So if I just think
as a fiduciary, I probably want to see resolution to some of the tough questions before risking my
five billion in assets, right? Clients, I think, are going to ask these banks the exact same
questions they ask us. And I'll rattle off a few that are top of mind in every conversation that
we have. Scope Battle Tested is this platform, right? Has it supported billions at scale?
On liability, this is super important. What's the framework there? And in this specific area,
are you really treating crypto as a first-class citizen alongside any other asset classes you're
serving? How large is your crypto insurance program? And what are the inclusions and exclusions
on that policy? From a resourcing perspective, are you putting the full weight of your firm
behind the crypto business substantively in terms of dollars and liability and engineering?
Or is this more of really a marketing type of thing under a brand, but substantively kind of
hived off? We've seen a little bit of that over the years. Commercially, right? This is a huge
question. What are you charging me for this platform? And does the sort of risk reward here
make sense? There's a business continuity question as well, I think. Is your crypto business going
to be around in five years or get cut when there's a rainy day? And I think the most important
question of all, what's your security budget for crypto safekeeping? Are you really succeeding
in hiring the crypto security talent that you should have to make this work? So looking at all
this from 10,000 feet, I think it's really easy for people to underestimate what goes into making
the crypto custody sausage. And the discerning clients are going to ask these questions. And
I think either want to work with Coinbase directly or maybe supplement that with one
of our subcustodial partners where they can still benefit from these things I've described. So let's
see how it all shakes out. We're super excited about the path we're on right now. I think the
other mental model I have for this is how many companies in the history of this industry have
been successful without the leader at the very top of that company being fully bought in. And a lot
of these banks just don't have that, right? So it's kind of hard to see building a scaled franchise
without senior leadership that's fully bought in because you're going to have bumps in the road
and you need someone that will stay the path. It's such a good point. And I think we've talked
about this in some of our prior conversations, Matt. One of the fundamental challenges that
you have in navigating this industry is just that for better or for worse, it's been highly cyclical.
And so when you're a firm that's doing 40 things and crypto is maybe one of them that you're
considering and it's potentially a small part of your business, and then you're also looking at
what's been a fairly cyclical growth story in crypto, I think that decision to have
resource and continuity and stay the course and really bet on this becomes super challenging.
And we've seen some financial institutions struggle with that. Now there's definitely
others who have really started to get this and make it work, but it's a fundamental challenge
that they have as they think about how to get this done. Yeah. So I want to talk about the
government stuff too here. So a lot of recent announcements around the government's involvement
in this industry, some good, some very bad, I would say. And I know Coinbase plays a role
in the safeguarding of assets, but also curious your view on strategic reserve and
just overall how you guys think about that government sector.
Sir, the announcement of the reserve earlier in March has appropriately received a ton of
attention. And it's also sort of a pinch me moment for those of us, I think, who have been
in the industry for a while, like, wow, how do we get here on the sideline? Coinbase works with
more than 150 government agencies around the world. And our job is really to try to show up
as a tactical partner on trade execution, security and asset safekeeping and ops.
These are areas where we think we have the track record and the credibility to assist.
And we'll try to apply that same approach in dealing with the U.S. reserve. I think one thing
that really resonates with our government partners has been our approach to regulation.
So we practically sought out the most stringent regulators time and time again as a strategy,
like the New York Department of Financial Services, of course, CFTC for our futures business.
For government, I think seeing the strength of those regulatory relationships,
as well as the fact that we're a publicly traded company in the U.S., have really resonated.
Taking my Coinbase hat off maybe for a minute, and I'm going to make our lawyers and comms people
sweat, but I'll say that just as an American citizen and a taxpayer, I'm personally most
excited about the versions of this reserve in the future that feel durable, strategic,
and fiscally responsible. So I know our mutual friend, Nick, is a bit of a skeptic on this whole
thing. I'm a little bit more positive. I think if we look at the gold reserve, which has a present
market value of something north of five or $600 billion, it probably makes sense to have a hard
asset reserve in our fiscally tenuous situation. That's not crazy to me. So if you think about
potentially reallocating a portion of that portfolio for the 21st century to include
Bitcoin or digital gold, I think that could be totally reasonable and reflects a lot of the
thinking we've already seen from many of the large investment firms we deal with
in the private markets. So I think if a hardliner libertarian wants to say that
reserves altogether are silly, I can understand that. But if we're going to keep the gold in
there and think about having a hard asset reserve, then put some Bitcoin in there too. I think that
could make sense. Yeah. Well, I guess the key word in what you said I think is durable. You
don't want something that every four years a politician can just press a button and liquidate
or buy it back, right? If we're going to do it, let's be thoughtful about it.
I think that's exactly right. So when you think about outside of what we've maybe talked about on
this podcast, what are you the most excited about just in this industry over the next year?
So many things. It feels like the kind of part of the growth journey where we're all going to
bed at every night and you had 40 things you wanted to get done or focus on and you kind of
did five of them. And so I think the focus on prioritization right now is a huge challenge.
I'll say that one area I'm really excited about that we're honing in on is corporate payments
and just what we're seeing with these enterprises really starting to embrace
stable points. So maybe Stripe's acquisition of Bridge was sort of the warning shot here
to the industry. You have super smart founders in that case making a really big invisible bet
who see the opportunity and have a lot to lose by missing it. So that's a huge signal.
And on our side, the last year has been really transformational. A lot of the large corporates
last year were looking at this as sort of a due diligence or a proof of concept exercise.
And now they're alive and paying partners and clients or accounts receivable are coming their
way in stable points. So we focused on a few things, I think, to start to kind of lubricate
this new payment network. One is integration with, of course, the major ERP systems that
underpin all this. And another is like the unsexy nitty gritty work of really supporting more fiat
onramps. So we can do really the end to end transaction lifecycle in as many kind of
geographies and currencies as we can, right? You can't just kind of only build things in the on
chain crypto snow globe, although sometimes it's fun to talk about that. You really have to marry
that world of the on chain transactions with the less exciting but critically important on and
off ramps to give these clients what they need. And that's all really coming together right now.
So I'm super excited. I think you end up here with an entirely new pavement rail, which is global 24
7 fast and super cheap and just gives a ton of credence to this notion that crypto has real
utility. And we're excited about how this is playing out. What about you, Matt? What are you
thinking about? Well, clearly, I mean, stable coins, I'm glad we hit on it, because if you just look
at the blockchains themselves and what they're being used for, I think on some days it's north
of 70% of every transaction that happens on a blockchain is a stable coin money movement.
And you just see the proliferation of dollars internationally. And it's clear that this is just
a breakout consumer use case where people have figured out a way to send money to their relatives
using dollars and people in non US jurisdictions have figured out a way that they can actually have
a basically US bank account just with having an Ethereum or Solana wallet for the first time.
And I think the B2B side of that is just going to follow. It's interesting to think about what these
legacy remittance models even look like in a future where you don't need to tie up capital
in different bank accounts all the way around the world to facilitate these payments. And
it actually turns out that this is just a great technology for that. It's not like a 2x improvement,
it's a 10x improvement in money movement. I think that's totally right. Yeah,
we're still early ish, but there's just more data points, I think, validating what you just said.
And for those incumbents in the money movement business, they're going to have a sort of
innovators dilemma question of when to start to disrupt themselves. And so I think that's like
coming soon to a feeder near you. And we're really excited to be helping push the envelope there.
Guess the other thing I'm super excited about is just what does the market structure look like in
the US around just general trading? Like even outside of spot? Do you end up with more venues?
Do you end up with different cast of characters? How does the liquidity landscape evolve if you
have a market structure bill where you have a security token model plus a commodity token model?
Are they together? I think there's just a lot of interesting questions there. And firms that are
able to see that early and build for that will be very, very well positioned. I agree with that.
I think we can expect a lot of change. Obviously, if the market structure
bill that we've been discussing comes to fruition at some point, that's going to
totally change things and I think accelerate this race. But even until then, we see a ton of
movement. And I think by the end of the year, we'll have a lot more exchanges and brokers
in the market and increasing overall liquidity for the industry as a whole, but also benefiting
Coinbase. And we're super excited about that. This has been great, Brian. Where can we send
people to learn more about what you're up to at Coinbase?
Sure. You can find us on our website at coinbase.com slash institutional. And you can also subscribe to
our market commentary through that page where our trading and research teams talk about the
trends that they're seeing in the market. Awesome. Well, thanks again for coming on.
Exciting stuff. Thanks a lot, Matt, for having me.
To listen to all of our podcast episodes, please go to onthebrink-podcast.com
or just click on the tab on our website. Thanks for listening.